(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T21:53:35.498057",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
鷹嶺ルイ 生誕LIVE 「Luminous Stairs」
Takane Lui Birthday Live "Luminous Stairs"
超重大 3D新衣装お披露目
[Huge Announcement: 3D New Outfit Reveal]
告知あり
[Special Announcement Included]
走りなさい 早く
Run, quickly,
もっと早く
even faster,
哀しみに追いつかれないように
so that sorrow cannot catch up to you.
探しなさい 明かりの
Search for the road
灯る道を
where lights are lit.
それは それは
That will surely, surely
眩しいでしょう
be dazzling, won't it?
挑みなさい 君の
Go face those
美しさや尊さを
who would harm your beauty
傷つけるものに
and your dignity.
眠りなさい 疲れれば
Sleep, when you are tired,
眠りなさい
just sleep,
神話を持たないあの
like those constellations
星座のように
that have no myths.
手を離したあと
After letting go of my hand,
君は気づくだろう
you will probably notice...
指の形 体温
...the shape of my fingers, my body heat,
その名残りが胸を刺す
and how their remnants pierce your chest.
忘れたことも
Even the things you forgot,
忘れてしまえ
forget them completely.
哀しみも温もりも消えてしまえ
Let both sorrow and warmth vanish away.
されど今も
And yet, even now,
耳に残るは
what remains in my ears...
固く再会を乞うような
...is like a firm wish to meet again...
さよなら
Goodbye...
I do, I do
I love, and you
踊りなさい
Dance...
誰に笑われても
...even if anyone laughs at you.
淡雪を払う枝のように
Like a branch brushing off light snow...
叫びなさい
Scream...
心から叫びなさい
...scream from your heart.
ここに確かにいたんだと響かせて
Make it echo that you were indeed here.
行き合いの空に 遠花火がにじむ
In the crossing sky, distant fireworks blur.
帰るべき家を捜す
Searching for a home to return to...
長い長い旅路を行くなら合わな
...if you go on a long, long journey.
高鳴らせ その心臓を
Let your heart beat fast and loud...
最期のひと打ちまで君のものだ
...it is yours until the very last beat.
涙、涙、溢れるがいい
Let the tears, tears overflow...
この鼓動が君の守り歌を歌うだろう
For this heartbeat will sing your lullaby.
それは千年のホームシックだった
It was a thousand years of homesickness...
無限さえも数え終えて
...even counting to infinity has ended.
怪物のような世界の隅っこで
In the corner of a monster-like world...
戦い続ける人 君はエル エル
...a person who continues to fight, you are El, El...
旅は続く
The journey continues.
忘れたことも忘れてしまう前
Before you forget even what you forgot...
哀しみも温もりも消えちまえ
...let both sorrow and warmth disappear.
今はもう君のことだけを
Now, only you are in my mind...
固く裂いた愛を願うような さよなら
...a goodbye that wishes for a tightly torn love.
I do, I do
I love, and you
駄目駄目駄目 脳みその中から
No, no, no! From inside my brain...
やめろ馬鹿と喚くモラリティ
...the morality that screams, "Stop it, you fool!"
ダーリン ベイビー ダーリン
Darling, baby, darling...
半端なくラブときらめき浮き足立つフィロソフィー
...a philosophy that sheds its shimmering, light-footed love.
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
An upturned glance so cute it's to die for.
なにかし法に触れるくらい
Enough to bordering on illegal somehow.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering wild thoughts, when I notice, I'm a stranger.
この世に生まれて君が悪い
You, who was born into this world, are to blame.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
A ridiculously painful lovesickness.
バラバラになる頭とこの身体
My head and this body are falling to pieces.
頸動脈から「アイラブユー」が吹き出て
From my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out.
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do with these feelings, what should I do?
あばらの奥をザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
The rock sugar deep in my guts is melting, I feel like I'll vomit.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Opening my pupils, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this world, you alone are the grand prize.
ひっくり返っても勝ちようない
Even if I flip over, I can't win.
君だけルールは適用外
The rules don't apply to you alone.
四つともオセロは黒しかない
All four corners of Othello are black.
カツアゲ放題
It's all-you-can-shake-down.
君が笑顔で放ったアバダケダブラ
The "Avada Kedavra" you unleashed with a smile...
デコにスティグマ 申し訳ねえな
...a stigma on my forehead, sorry about that.
矢を刺して
Stab me...
貫いて
...pierce through me...
ここ弱点
...here's my weak point!
死ぬほど可愛い上目遣い
An upturned glance so cute it's to die for.
なにかし法に触れるくらい
Enough to bordering on illegal somehow.
ばら撒く乱心 気づけば蕩尽
Scattering wild thoughts, when I notice, I'm a stranger.
この世に生まれて君が悪い
You, who was born into this world, are to blame.
パチモンでもいい 何でもいい
Even a cheap imitation is fine, anything is fine.
今君と名付けてる全て欲しい
Right now, I want everything named after you.
頸動脈から「アイラブユー」が吹き出て<
From my carotid artery, "I love you" gushes out.
アイリスアウト
Iris out.
一体どうしよう この想いをどうしよう
What on earth should I do with these feelings, what should I do?
あばらの奥をザラメが溶けて ゲロになりそう
The rock sugar deep in my guts is melting, I feel like I'll vomit.
瞳孔バチ開いて 溺れ死にそう
Opening my pupils, I feel like I'm drowning and dying.
今この世で君だけ大正解
Right now, in this world, you alone are the grand prize.
解体世界
Dismantled world
Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling Darling
永遠の意味知らぬ君に
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show the answer,
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
into the end of the spiral that follows the illusion.
夢幻
[Song: Mugen (Illusion)]
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason that sounded like an excuse
儚い未来手繰り寄せた弱さ
is the fleeting weakness of drawing in the future,
それを強さとはき違えている
mistakenly taken as strength.
憎い 憎い
Hateful, hateful...
醜い 醜い
Ugly, ugly...
月を隠すほどの
so much as to hide the moon.
黒く 黒く
Black, black...
淀む 心
stagnant heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you were not here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を割く
tearing our hearts like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show the answer,
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
at the end of the spiral following the illusion,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲んだ
Born into this fate I accepted,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
I remembered the names of the numbers I bore.
爛れるほど心燃やす感情
An emotion that burns the heart to the point of festering.
憎い 憎い
Hateful, hateful...
醜い 醜い
Ugly, ugly...
世界を分かつほどの
so much as to divide the world.
怒り 怒り
Anger, anger...
燃やす 心
burning heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you were not here.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を割く
tearing our hearts like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show the answer,
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
at the end of the spiral following the illusion,
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞いよ
I listened to the wail of ghosts, and this is the end.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
Everything that resides in this body ends here.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
A weak person who entrusted the dream to others.
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The radiance of life in the passing of time...
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
In the setting sun illuminated by the flickering of prayers...
千夜を身に宿し
Bearing a thousand nights in this body,
解を押し付ける
forcing an answer.
枯らしていく 枯らしていく
Withering away, withering away,
夢幻の夜に花を割く
tearing flowers in the dreamless night.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく
Connecting, connecting,
嵐に種を播いていく
sowing seeds in the storm.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる
Swaying, swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like flowers.
奪っていく 奪っていく
Taking away, taking away,
嵐のように心を割く
tearing our hearts like a storm.
永遠の意味知らぬ君に
To you who knows not the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show the answer,
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
at the end of the spiral following the illusion,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
ということで、ねこに、あ、にこに来ていただきました！
And with that, Neko... ah, Niko is here with us today!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！にこたんです！
Happy birthday! I'm Niko-tan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
よく抑えきれたな！
You did so well holding back your tears!
なんかもうね、顔が...
Right? My face is already...
顔はもう涙で滲んでいる！
My face is already smeared with tears!
「大丈夫か？」って
"Are you okay?" they're asking.
いやいや、ありがとうございます。こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you so much, likewise.
ということで、2026年の生誕祭はですね、
And so, for my 2026 Birthday Festival...
あの、ニコさんがゲスト出演ということで。
Niko-san is here as our guest star!
あの、ニコさんもね、3Dになったということで。
Niko-san has finally got her 3D model, too!
で、ニコさんが「いつかルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って言ってくれてたので。
Since you said you wanted to sing by my side one day,
なので、今日はお呼びさせていただきました！
I decided to invite you today!
ありがとうございます、本当に。
Thank you so much, really.
いや、めちゃくちゃかっこいい曲をね、ちょっと歌わせていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたか？
Well, we just got to sing a super cool song. Everyone, how did you like it?
「ニコちゃん良かったね」って。
Everyone is saying, "I'm glad for you, Niko-chan!"
いや、もうニコちゃんのことはいいんですよ！
Oh, never mind about me!
「ニコちゃん良かったね」って。
"I'm so glad for you, Niko-chan!"
そんなことよりですよ、ルイ先輩、今日重大告知もあるし。
More importantly, Lui-senpai! Today there's a major announcement,
そうなんです。新、新、新衣装も。
That's right! And a ne-ne-new outfit!
新衣装もあるんです。
Yes, a new outfit too!
出るんでしたっけ？
Is it coming out?
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ、「鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕ライブ」ってありますので、
We have this hashtag on screen, "Takane Lui Super Major Birthday Live,"
それでたくさんたくさんポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど。
so I'd love it if you all posted a lot using it!
今日はたくさん告知もありますし。
We have so many announcements today, too.
そうですよね！
Absolutely!
いや、ニコちゃん気になるのも、重大告知のデカさも気になるんですけど、
I'm curious about the scale of the major announcement,
新衣装がやっぱね、気になる。
but I'm especially eager to see the new outfit!
やっぱ、ルイ先輩っていえばちょっとダークネスな感じなのかな、とか思って。黒、黒系なのかなみたいな。
I wonder if it'll have a dark feel, since that's your vibe, senpai. Like black-themed?
ああ、なるほど、なるほど。そう思いますよね。
Ah, I see, I see. You'd think so, right?
ま、それもあります。
Well, there is that.
おおっ！それも？
Oh! That too?
最初ね、あの、固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど。
At first, as I wrote in the pinned message...
あの、新衣装は最初サブカラー。
The new outfit is actually in a sub-color first!
ええっ！？
What?!
で、ちょっと清楚な感じの衣装になっております。
And it has a somewhat pure, elegant look.
え、それもある？他、他にもあるってこと？
Eh, you have that too? Meaning there are others?
はい、めちゃくちゃ大量にサブを用意しておりますので、最後までね、楽しみに...
Yes, we have prepared a massive amount of variations, so please look forward to it...
なんか、なんかすごい騒いでる。お返し、お返し。
She's getting super hyper. Back to your place, back to your place!
さ、サブが！？
S-Sub-colors?!
もういいや、今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Anyway, thank you for coming today!
あ、分かりました。じゃあ、あの、楽屋で応援してます。それでは。
Ah, okay. Then I'll cheer you on from the dressing room. Goodbye!
あ、違います、違います。そ、そちらの舞踏会会場なんで。
Ah, wait, no. That way leads to the ballroom hall.
これ、行っちゃダメなんですか、ニコちゃん？
Am I not allowed to go there?
はい、ニコちゃんは呼んでない。招待状、もらってないでしょ？
Yes, you weren't invited. You didn't get an invitation, did you?
もらってないけど...
I didn't, but...
うん、じゃあ、あの、すみませんが楽屋の方に、あちらから。
Right, so please head back to the dressing room. That way.
はい、スタッフさんお願いします。
Staff, please take care of her.
ルイ先輩、また自分無理いって...
Lui-senpai, sorry for being so stubborn...
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
ありがとう、ありがとうね。
Thank you, thank you!
はい、新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので、最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
Yes, I'll be showing off plenty of the new outfit, so please enjoy it until the very end.
楽屋のニコちゃんも楽しんでくださいね。
Enjoy the show from the dressing room too, Niko-chan!
それでは、聞いてください。「ZIG-ZAG」
And now, please listen to "ZIG-ZAG".
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four
『幸せ？』って囁いた問いがラッタ タラッタ
The whispered question "Are you happy?" went rat-tat-tarat-tat
こびり憑いて離れんは駄目だ ラッタ タラッタ
It clings to me and won't leave, it's no use, rat-tat-tarat-tat
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember my tasteless, odorless life anymore
忘れたいから歌った 馬鹿だ ラッタ タラッタ
I sang because I wanted to forget, I'm such a fool, rat-tat-tarat-tat
恨むことも憎むことも賢くない故出来なかった
Resenting or hating, I couldn't do either since I wasn't clever enough
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your conclusion...
笑ってしまいたいほど嘘 嘘 嘘
It makes me want to just laugh it off as a lie, lie, lie...
「嘘つき」
"Liar."
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, it hurts, wishing for a bit of a miracle
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌！ タチが悪いわ痕
I'm sick of it, sick, sick, sick, sick of it! How malicious
ねえ 辛い lie lie lie 否？ おかしいとこ全部抉り取って
Hey, is it painful? Lie, lie, lie, right? Gouging out every single anomaly
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
You can call me heartless, call me whatever you like
トラウマにバイバイしたいの ですです で・で・で・です
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma, I really do!
私、甘え上手になれなかった
I was never good at playing the spoiled one
可愛げとかが足りなかった
I simply lacked charm
後悔が煩い夜だった
It was a night filled with noisy regrets
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば？
"Why not just accept the past as past?"
きっといいコトあるさとか
"Surely something good will happen," they say
それくらい百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I know that all too well, rat-tat-tat
願うことも祈ることも許されないから黒く染めた
Since wishing and praying are forbidden to me, I dyed it all black
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color anymore
絡んだ運命の糸 糸 糸 糸
The tangled threads of fate
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, it hurts
悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
Acting like a tragic heroine
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌！
I'm sick of it, sick, sick, sick, sick of it!
諦めちまえば？
"Why don't you just give up?"
でも 会いたい たい たい たいな
But I want to see you, see you, see you
思考回路がこんがらがっちゃって
My train of thought is completely tangled up
明日またきっと壊すけどいいの
I'll surely break it again tomorrow, but that's fine
壊すけどいいの？
I'll break it down, but is that okay?
トラウマさえ愛して
Love me, even my trauma,
です・です・て・です・です
desu, desu, te, desu, desu!
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I am holding hands with you,
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
just like we were back then, knowing nothing.
でも分かっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I will wake up soon.
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと葬り去って
If so, I'd rather you gently bury me with your own hands.
ほら 今、今、今
Look, now, now, now!
歪んだ 会いたい 会いたい 会いたいな
My distorted longing to see you, see you, see you...
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
I'm starting to hope for a bit of a miracle.
もう 嫌・嫌・嫌・嫌・嫌・嫌
I hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it, hate it!
タチが悪い割に
Despite how nasty it is,
足りない 足りない 足りないな
it's not enough, not enough, not enough.
おかしなとこ全部えぐり取って
Gouge out all the strange parts.
薄情って結構
Calling me heartless is fine,
お好きに呼んでいいよ
you can call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいので
Since I want to say bye-bye to my trauma...
です・です・て・です・です です・です・て・です・です
desu, desu, te, desu, desu! Desu, desu, te, desu, desu!
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
An unwavering justice that deceives the world,
ほどいて真実この手のなか
I will untangle the truth within these hands.
アイのシナリオ
[Title: Ai no Scenario]
大胆不敵な影が 華麗に舞う
A bold and fearless shadow dances magnificently.
君が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせてよ
Tell me someday the secret you are hiding.
伸ばした手で触れるものは 誰も信じられない
Even if I reach out, I can't trust anyone I touch,
君が隠してる世界 僕に見せてよ
show me the world you are hiding.
揺れる難解な心 解き明かして 奪うその瞳
I will solve your swaying, complex heart and steal away those eyes.
不安がって泣いてたって見つからないよ
Even if you cry in anxiety, you won't find it.
狙う真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the targeted truth disappear to?
たとえ
Even if...
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
an unwavering justice deceives the world,
解いて真実差し出す手のひら
I will untangle the truth and reach out my hand.
決して逃げない 怖くはないから
I will never run away, because I am not afraid.
目を開けて弱さをかき消したんだ
I've opened my eyes and wiped away my weakness.
繰り返される運命に 君は気づいてる？
Are you aware of this repeating destiny?
僕が隠してる秘密 いつか聞かせるよ
I'll tell you someday the secret I am hiding.
歩み寄る偽りの影 君は知らない
You don't know the false shadow drawing near.
芽生えた記憶は絡む 必然の棘で
The sprouting memories entangle with the thorns of destiny.
守りたい思い出ただ 立ち向かって解くその絆
Confronting everything just to protect our memories, I'll untangle that bond.
何度だって助けるって 揺らぎはしないよ
My vow to save you over and over will never waver.
隠す真実はどこへ消えた
Where did the hidden truth disappear to?
たとえ
Even if...
世界を敵に回したとしても
I turn the entire world against me,
信じて僕だけ 未来も
believe only in me, and our future.
決して逃げない 迷いはないから
I will never run away, because I have no doubts.
シナリオを壊して抗うんだ
I will break the scenario and fight back!
世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if I turn the world against me,
信じて差し出す手のひら
I believe and reach out my palm.
決して放さない
I'll never let go,
答えは届いた
the answer has reached.
結んだ運命
The tied fate
この手の中
is inside these hands.
繰り返された後悔だとしても
Even if it's a repeated regret...
決して逃げない
I will never run away,
怖くはないから
because I am not afraid.
抗うんだ
I will resist!
何度も 何度も 走り続けるよ
Over and over, I'll keep running!
Wake up! 闘志昂進
Wake up! Fighting spirit rising!
Shift up! ギア回して
Shift up! Shift the gears!
Speed up! 羽ばたいて
Speed up! Spread your wings!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
Jump up! 天辺へ
Jump up! To the very top!
Turn up! 声合わせて
Turn up! Join our voices!
Dream up! 未来繋いで
Dream up! Connect the future!
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
最高潮コンディション 闘志ガンガン尖ってこう
Top-notch condition, let's sharpen our fighting spirit!
栄光のチャンピオン 虎視眈々と狙ってこう
Glory's champion, let's keep our eyes on the prize!
My paceより High pace
Rather than my own pace, high pace!
気合レースに超集中
Super focused on this energetic race!
駆けるセオリーは限界ハートに誓い
The theory of running, sworn to my limit-breaking heart,
U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮アンビション 描いた軌動勝負
Climax ambition, a battle on the drawn path!
千載一遇のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでこう
Let's give it our all to grab this once-in-a-lifetime chance!
My paceより High pace
Rather than my own pace, high pace!
気合レースに猛進中
Rushing forward in this energetic race!
駆けるフォームをリセット 勝ち上がってこう
Reset the running form, let's win our way up!
共々二人競い合った風の中でも
Even in the wind where the two of us competed,
大きな背中追いかけてた雨の中でも
even in the rain where I chased your big back,
何百何千回と積み重ねてきた
we've piled it up hundreds, thousands of times.
だからどこまでも遠く
So, let's go far, wherever we can,
どこまでも高く
higher and higher!
誰よりも早く
Faster than anyone else,
誰よりも強く
stronger than anyone else!
さあ今！
Now, at this very moment!
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
These running feelings will never stop!
誰にも渡せないゴールまで
Until the goal that I won't give up to anyone!
弱気な気持ち蹴飛ばして 一等星目指し進もう
Kick away any weakness, let's march towards the brightest star!
立ち上がって走り抜け
Rise up and run through!
鳴り出した鼓動はもう収まらない
The beating heart that started ringing will never calm down!
最後まで前進全力 全霊をかけて
Moving forward with all our might and soul until the very end!
頂点へと手を伸ばして
Reaching our hands out to the summit,
限界さえ超えてゆく
we will surpass even our limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へと
Overtaking legends, heading towards victory!
共々二人競い合ったあの喜びも
The joy of competing together as two,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
the admiration of chasing your big back,
何千何万回と生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn thousands, millions of times,
何度も
over and over,
走り続けるよ
we'll keep running!
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
These running feelings will never stop!
誰もが夢に見てる未来まで
Until the future that everyone dreams of!
渋きも 傷も 迷いも 思い出だってずっと
The splashes, the wounds, the doubts, and even the memories, always...
全てを繋いでゆけ
Connect everything together!
さあ今！
Now, at this very moment!
鳴り出した鼓動はもう収まらない
The beating heart that started ringing will never calm down!
最後まで前進全力 全霊をかけて
Moving forward with all our might and soul until the very end!
頂点へと手を伸ばして
Reaching our hands out to the summit,
限界さえ超えてゆけ
surpass even our limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へと
Overtaking legends, heading towards victory!
共々二人競い合ったあの喜びも
The joy of competing together as two,
大きな背中追いかけてたあの憧れも
the admiration of chasing your big back,
何千何万回と生まれ変わっても
even if we are reborn thousands, millions of times,
何度も
over and over,
走り続けるよ
we'll keep running!
覚ませ本能を 起こせ感動を
Awaken your instinct! Stir up emotion!
突き詰めろ伝説を 叫べ Break out!
Pursue the legend! Shout, Break out!
Hey! Hey! Wow wow wow
Hey! Hey! Break break break out!
絡んだって悔しがるのか
Are you frustrated that you got tangled up?
錆びついていたいのか 狼狽えているのか
Do you want to rust away, or are you just panicking?
諦め悪く這い上がり這い出すんだ
Refusing to give up, crawl up and push forward!
目を離すな 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
Don't look away, we're going to rewrite history!
だんだんだんだんだんだん上がってく
Step by step, we're climbing up!
歓声巻き起こすデッドヒート
A dead heat that stirs up cheers!
だんだんだんだんだんだん迫ってく
Step by step, we're closing in!
あと少し 鬩ぎ合うシンパシー
Just a bit more, our conflicting sympathies!
最上で挑みたい
I want to challenge at my very best!
最高を掴みたい
I want to grasp the absolute best!
(Fight on!) 挑みたい
Fight on! I want to challenge...
(Fight on!) 掴みたい
Fight on! I want to seize...
(Fight on!) 伝えたい
Fight on! I want to convey!
革命の火蓋切って
Cutting open the fire of revolution,
伝説の旗掲げてゆこう さぁ
let's hoist the flag of legend! Come on!
さぁ Legend Changer ロックに飛び込んで
Come on, Legend Changer, dive into the rock!
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become a player who creates enthusiasm!
Legend Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend Changer, let's go boldly!
本能醒ませSafe
Awaken your instincts,
感動起こせ
ignite the excitement,
伝説刻んで
carve your legend,
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!
kick the ground, kick, kick, break!
長い長い夢の旅路を
On this long, long dream journey,
一歩また一歩と 確実に進んでいく
I'll advance step by step, with certainty.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に
Beyond where I gaze with a sharp look...
みんなの笑顔があると信じて
さぁいくよ！
believing there are everyone's smiles,
高みへ！
now let's go! To the heights!
無数に差し込む熱に観る栄冠を
The crown of glory we see in the countless rays of heat,
憧れにして終わらせるな
don't let it end as a mere aspiration.
託された夢が隙間を切って
The entrusted dream cuts through the gap,
今 私たちの明日へと 変わっていく
now changing into our tomorrow.
さぁ Legend Changer ロックに飛び込んで
Come on, Legend Changer, dive into the rock!
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
Become a player who creates enthusiasm!
Legend Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend Changer, let's go boldly!
本能醒ませ
Awaken your instincts,
感動起こせ
ignite the excitement,
伝説刻んで
carve your legend,
大地蹴って 蹴って 蹴って break!
kick the ground, kick, kick, break!
(Wo-o-o wo-o-o)
(Break break break out!)
もう救えない スクライブばかりのプルペンじゃ
There's no saving it, in a bullpen full of scrubs.
ちゃちな青春も お涙も それすらもないもんな
Even cheap youth and tears too, none of that is left.
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならないSimple
Can't even laugh about it, a one-scene comedy won't go right either.
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わした さもそんな人生さ
Just mixing cold chowder, that's life, isn't it?
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを
How long should I keep pretending not to see
いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
the look of my misplaced buttons?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Right, there's no room for excuse.
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで
Accidentally ran into a fire,
善かれと油を放り込んで
and threw in some oil as a kindness,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
life, plans, it's all turning into potatoes.
ぐつぐつ明日が泡吹いてSimple
Bubbling, tomorrow is foaming,
白目のままに茹で上がって
I'm being boiled with my eyes rolled back.
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
Future portraits, success methods, it's all turning into potatoes.
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Just like this, we all soak and scatter,
どろどろに未来を溶かして
melting the future into a sludge.
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
Living in this kind of life, let's go and get KUSHA KUSHA!
もう時間がない 我らに見下す権利などない
Simple
There's no time left, we have no right to look down on anything.
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
The boos sent by the masses are a medal now.
相当に笑えない 誰だってそう言わざるを得ない
Can't even laugh, everyone has to say that.
バカの一つ覚えのように 空回って ただバターになっている
Like a fool, tangling up and just becoming butter.
始めはこんなつもりじゃなかった
I didn't intend for it to be like this at first,
誰か信じてくれやしないか
won't someone believe me?Simple
一切、反証の余地はないが
Not that there's any room for counter-evidence, though.Simple
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で
As if nothing happened,
ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
here's my chance, throwing in firewood,
生活も 計画も 全部がpotatoになっていく
life, plans, it's all turning into potatoes.
こんがり明日が煮え切って
Nicely browned, tomorrow is cooked,
姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
burning so high I can't even see myself.Simple
将来像 成功法 全部がpotatoになっていく
Future portraits, success methods, it's all turning into potatoes.
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Just like this, we all soak and scatter,
どろどろに未来を溶かしてSimple
melting the future into a sludge.
そんなボウルの中で うさ晴らしだとかしようぜ
Let's just vent in that kind of bowl!
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA KUSHAになっていこうぜ
Living in this kind of life, let's go and get KUSHA KUSHA!
Welcome to the wonderland
ここでは誰もが淫ら
where everyone here is tainted.
How are you doing, miss?
But you're tempted by the moonlight
どうせ足掻いても無駄
No matter how you struggle, it's useless...
死ぬまで還れない
...you can't go back until you die.
不気味な猫が黒の中で嗤う
An eerie cat leers in the darkness...
「こんなにも濡れてるじゃアないか」
"...My, aren't you quite wet?"
官能へ響く嬌声にそっと耳を澄まし
Gently listen to the sweet voice echoing in ecstasy,
まるでアリスのように
just like Alice.
殺さぬように 逝かせぬように
So as not to kill you, or let you finish,
壊れるまで愛してあげる
I will love you until you break.
快楽は媚薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac...
どんな兵もやがて犬のように跪くのよ
...that will make any soldier kneel like a dog.
This love is so insane
「そうこれは夢の中、童話の魔女が出てきた光景」
"Yes, this is a dream, a fairy tale witch's scene."
Birthdayでもないのに御馳走
It's not your birthday, yet here's a feast,
優しい仮面もスリ落ちそうで
and the mask of kindness seems about to slip off.
「ねぇいつものママはどこ？」
"Hey, where's my usual mom?"
それも気づかずに
Without even noticing that,
If I am dreaming
Somebody wake me up
Off with their heads!
そしてメアリーアンは走り
And then Mary Anne ran,
帽子屋がまたカラカラと歌う
and the Hatter sings clattering away once more.
誰も皆嘘で嘘を塗り潰す時
When everyone covers up lies with more lies,
仮面の裏が見える
you can see what's behind the mask.
侵さぬように 汚さぬように
So as not to violate, or defile you,
色欲を咲かす花園
this is a garden where lust blooms.
この蜜が欲しいなら
If you want this nectar,
膝をつき血を舐め愛を述べ
get on your knees, lick up the blood, and profess your love.
さあ心臓を捧げて頂戴
Now, offer up your heart to me.
Yes, your majesty
I cut out my heart for you
殺さぬように 逝かせぬように
So as not to kill you, or let you finish,
この狂気のディナーさえ味わうほど
savoring even this dinner of madness...
あたしは
...I am...
The Queen of Hearts
夢幻クライマックス
[Title: Mugen Climax]
さよなら 甘い街
Goodbye, sweet city...
私をくれた人
...and the one who made me who I am.
泣き癖 笑い合い
My crying habits, laughing together,
理屈のない喜び
a joy with no logic.
曖昧 未完成の
Vague, incomplete...
過ち 悟ったけど
...mistakes I came to realize,
それは恋の季節
but that was the season of love...
閃きは戻らない
...and that spark won't return.
シナリオ通りのカルマ
The karma of scenarios
飛び越えてきた人生
a life spent jumping across.
望みがなくなって
Even if my wishes go away,
愛だけ残ったの
only love will be left behind.
それぞれの幸せ振りかざしても
Even if we brandish our respective happinesses,
倒れないふたりで立っていようね自屋
let's stand together as an unbreakable couple.
鮮やかでいてね
Stay vivid,
そのままのキミでいてね
stay just the way you are,
消えない幻想
an illusion that never disappears.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Phantasmagorical climax, the last night,
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
carve this endlessness innovatively.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい
Because even if you embrace me,
強くなりすぎたから
I've become so strong that I can't break.
あなたはわからない
You will never understand
抱えきれる空の孤独
the empty loneliness I hold.
それでも無神経に
Even so, insensitively,
季節が巡ってゆく
the seasons continue to turn.
いつも褒めてくれた 叱ってくれた
You always praised me, always scolded me,
金木犀の匂い 寂しくなるね
the scent of sweet osmanthus makes me lonely.
忘れないでいてね
Don't forget me,
憧れていてね
keep longing for me,
消えない面影
like a trace that never fades.
だからディスティニー 時を越えて
That's why destiny, transcending time,
同じ地球踏んでいられるわ
allows us to stand on the same earth.
魂だけ側に置いてね
Just keep my soul by your side,
強く生きていけるの
and I can live on strongly.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜
Phantasmagorical climax, the last night,
エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
carve this endlessness innovatively.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい
Because even if you embrace me,
強くなりすぎた
I've become so strong that I can't break.
…さみしい
...I'm lonely.
だからディスティニー 時を越えて
That's why destiny, transcending time,
同じ地球踏んでいられるわ
allows us to stand on the same earth.
魂だけ側に置いてね
Just keep my soul by your side,
強く生きていこうね
and let's live on strongly.
はい、ということで
All right, so...
ゲストパート見ていただきました、いかがだったでしょうか？
You've seen the guest part. How did you like it?
本当にね、あの、ゲストの人とこういうことをやりたいっていうのを
We really got to realize our wishes...
えー、実現させていただきました！
...to do things like this with our guests!
皆さん、出演ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for appearing!
はい、詳しくはですね、明日の振り返り配信で
Yes, for details, in tomorrow's review stream,
色々ね、裏話だったりとかをお話させていただこうかなと思いますので
I'll talk about various behind-the-scenes stories and such,
ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください！そして！
so please be sure to watch the review stream! And!
いかがですか？新衣装は！
How do you like... the new outfit?!
いかがでしょうか？可愛いでしょう？
What do you think? Pretty cute, right?
たくさん、あの、差分があったんですけど、気づきましたか？ま、気づきますよね！
There were many variations, did you notice? Well, of course you did!
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして
At first, it started with the white outfit,
そして「ウマニューワールド」ではですね、あの、黒いパンツ姿で階段から、そこの階段から登場したんですけれども
and in "Uma New World," I appeared in black pants, coming down those stairs.
最初、みんな「あれ？ルイどこ？」みたいな
At first, everyone was like, "Huh? Where is Lui?"
感じになってて面白かったんですけど、
which was really funny,
なんかね、ウマ娘を知っている人は「まあ、あそこから来るんやろうな」ってなんか
but those who know Umamusume probably thought, "Well, she'll probably come from there,"
後方腕組みしてたのがまた面白かったですね。
and crossed their arms in the back, which was also hilarious.
はい。えー、メイン、あの、このあとですね、えー、21時20分から
Yes. And next, from 21:20,
えー、メイン限で撮影会もございますので
we will have a member-only photo session,
そちらもぜひ、いろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので撮影会も
where I want to show you various outfit variations, so please...
ぜひ、来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます。
...come join the photo session as well. I'd be very happy.
はい、えー、重大発表はですね、このあと、あと2曲あるんですけど
Yes, as for the major announcement, there are two songs left,
えー、今から歌う曲のあとで、えー、発表させていただきますので
and we will announce it after the song I'm about to sing,
ぜひ皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただたらなと思います。
so please look forward to it!
はい、えー、じゃあ次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイ・セカンドアルバム「Lapis Lazuli」から一曲歌わせていただきます。
Now then, the next song is from Takane Lui's second album, "Lapis Lazuli."
「抗う君への鎮魂歌」です。お願いします。
It's "A Requiem for You Who Resist." Please enjoy.
抗う君への鎮魂歌
[Title: A Requiem for You Who Resist]
正しさだけ纏える術があれば
If only there was a way to clothe myself in righteousness,
少しは救われるだろうか？
would I be saved even just a little?
その瞳へと問いかける
I ask those eyes of yours.
護るべきを捨てるべきと
"What you should protect, you should abandon,"
誰かにかどわかされても
even if someone tries to deceive me with those words,
心通わないならそれは虚言だ
if our hearts don't connect, it is a lie.
何も
Without...
捨てずに
discarding anything,
抗う
to struggle...
力なき亡者
is a powerless phantom.
その覚悟無き創造に
In a creation without such resolve,
正しさなどない
there is no righteousness at all.
失えば失うほどに更に気高く
The more I lose, the nobler I become.
その意志で世界を恨め
Curse the world with that resolve.
心が軋んで何度引き裂かれようと抗え
Even if my heart creaks and is torn apart over and over, resist!
か弱き一人を
In order to protect
守り抜くためのこの手の平が
that single fragile person to the end,
どれだけ汚れてしまっても構わないさ
I don't care how dirty these palms of mine become.
君が笑うなら
If you will smile,
僕は何にでもなる
I will become anything.
浅ましい擬態
A miserable mimicry...
へつらうだけなら
if you do nothing but flatter,
人も獣も何一つ変わらない
humans and beasts are not one bit different.
鎖に似た自由を
Lamenting a freedom
嘆いては歪に愛でるのでしょう
that resembles chains, you probably love it in a distorted way.
どうか君だけは
Please, if only you
僕を覚えていて欲しい
would remember me.
必ず君を自由へと誘う
I will surely guide you to freedom.
俯けば俯くほどに更に気高く
The more I hang my head, the nobler I become.
その意志で世界を揺らせ
Shake the world with that resolve.
心が歪んで何もかもが崩れても抗え
Even if my heart is distorted and everything collapses, resist!
か弱き一人を
In order to protect
守り抜くためのこの手の平が
that single fragile person to the end,
どれだけ汚れてしまっても構わないさ
I don't care how dirty these palms of mine become.
君が笑うなら
If you will smile,
何度だって壊してみせる
I will destroy it over and over again.
心から君が笑えた時
When you can smile from the bottom of your heart,
僕は報われるのだろう
I will finally be rewarded.
消えかけた夢に
[Screen: To the fading dream]
ホロホロだけど
[Screen: Though I'm in pieces]
[Screen: 2026]
12.16
[Screen: 12.16]
不安も、
[Screen: Anxiety,]
否定も、
[Screen: denial,]
葛藤も。
[Screen: and conflict too.]
私が歌で「反逆」する。
[Screen: I will "rebel" through my song.]
1st Live 開催決定
[Screen: First Solo Live Confirmed!]
venue Kanadevia Hall
[Screen: Venue: Kanadevia Hall]
REBELLION Takane Lui 1st Live
[Screen: Takane Lui 1st Live: REBELLION]
ここから始まる。私だけの物語。
[Screen: It starts here. My own story.]
はい！ということで！
Yes! So!
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！
My, Takane Lui's, very first solo live concert has been confirmed!
イェーイ！
Yay!
フゥー！
Woo!
ということで、日程は半年後に、なる、なるのですが、
So, the date is in six months, well, it will be...
半年後の2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
six months from now, on Wednesday, December 16, 2026!
えー、会場は、Kanadevia Hallです！
The venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末にholoXのライブがありまして
As you know, we had the holoX live at the end of April,
そして9月にね、NEPOCSがありまして
then NEPOCS in September,
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで
and now a Takane Lui solo live in December.
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年になるんじゃないですか？ ルイトモさん。
Isn't 2026 going to be an incredibly fun year, Rui-tomo?
はい。ということで、ルイトモさんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれど、私は前々からですね...
Yes. So, while I think I've discussed this a lot with you, Rui-tomo,
えー、今まで音楽活動を、えー、で、道を作ってきてくれた先輩、そら先輩だったり、
I've admired seniors like Sora-senpai who paved the way in our music activities,
すいちゃん、あずちゃん、そしてわため、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね、ファーストライブから少しずつ...
Sui-chan, Azu-chan, Watame, and Calli-senpai...
えー、段階、階段を上がっていって、
taking it step by step, climbing the stairs from a first live,
広い会場でソロライブをするという、そんな物語に憧れていました。
and holding solo lives in larger venues. I've always admired that kind of story.
だからもし私がライブをやることになった際には、
So, if I were to ever hold a live concert,
ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォースと...
I wanted to go from first, second, third, to fourth...
順々に会場を大きくして、ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい、
gradually increasing the venue size, and eventually making my dream of an arena live come true.
はい、そう思っていて、えー、ルイトモさんには、えー、常々お伝えをしていたと思います。
Yes, that's what I thought, and I believe I've always shared that with you all.
えー、そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる、活動を頑張りたいなと思って、今まで努力をしてきました。
To achieve that, I've worked hard so I could hold regular solo lives.
そしてこれからもします！
And I will continue to do so!
えー、最近のホロライブはですね、結構、より多くの方が入る会場での開催が多くて、
Lately, Hololive concerts are often held in much larger venues,
私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは、思っていたんですけれども、
which made me wonder if my dream would be a bit difficult to achieve.
こうやって、私の夢を理解してくださり、叶えて、叶えるべく、
However, you understood my dream, and to help make it a reality,
まずは、私の希望だったKanadevia Hallにて、ファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！
we decided to hold my first live at my dream venue, Kanadevia Hall!
おめでとう、ありがとう！ そして、あのトレンドもありがとうございます、ありがとうございます。
Congratulations and thank you! Also, thank you so much for the trending topic!
えー、ここからが鷹嶺ルイの新章の、えー、新章の物語の始まりでございます。
This is the beginning of a new chapter in Takane Lui's story.
まずはファーストライブをね、開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれど、
I know I should focus on the first live before thinking about the next step,
私はセカンド、サード、フォース、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております。
but I've already envisioned the second, third, fourth, and even lives beyond that.
はい。今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように、ルミナスステアーズ、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために、
Yes. Just like the title of today's birthday live, "Luminous Stairs," to climb up those shining stairs,
そして、一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために、
and to spin this story together with you,
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は、えー、次にね、繋げるために、応募したり、ライブを見てくれると嬉しいです！
if you even slightly feel like going, I'd be so happy if you applied or watched the live to help connect us to the next step!
ライブのタイトルは、Rebellion、になっております。はい、Rebellionです。
The title of the live concert is "Rebellion." Yes, "Rebellion."
はい、反逆という意味でございます。私がいつも抱えている不安や、そして、色々な否定の声、
Yes, it means "Rebellion." The anxiety I always carry, the various critical voices,
そして私自身の葛藤、えー、これからも私は、えー、それを私の歌で反逆していきたい、そんな気持ちで込めさせて、えー、込めさせていただきました。
and my own inner conflicts... I want to rebel against them all through my songs. That's the feeling I poured into it.
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください！
I'm preparing a lot to make it the absolute best live, so please look forward to it!
はい、ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、アーティスト写真を作りました！ こちらです。
Now, as Takane Lui's story begins anew, we have a new artist photo! Here it is.
はい、えー、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこかわいい。
Yes, it looks incredibly cool. Cool and cute.
はい、アーティスト活動の際には、こちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
I plan on using this photo for my artist activities, so please look forward to seeing it.
そして、ここまでファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが、
And although I've released first and second albums, as well as an acoustic album,
今回、ライブを、えー、ライブを盛り上げるために、4曲、はい、
this time, to pump up the live concert, I've created four new songs!
えー、新しく作りまして、収録させていただいたミニアルバムも、本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です！
This mini-album containing the new recordings will be available for pre-order right after today's live!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。
We really have a lot of songs now, don't we, Takane Lui?
はい、えー、Soar, LEGENDARYという、はい、タイトルを付けさせていただきました、ミニアルバムでございます。
Yes, "LEGENDARY" is the title of this mini-album.
このあとにね、披露する新曲も入っております。
It also includes the new song that I'll perform later today.
えー、完全生産限定盤には全員にサインが付きます！ はい。
The complete limited edition comes signed for everyone! Yes.
完全生産限定盤には全員に、えー、直筆サインが付きますので、はい、ぜひ、日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください。
Since the complete limited edition will include a handwritten signature for everyone, I'll sign each one with my gratitude, so please pre-order it.
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。こちらはちょっとサイン付いてないんですけど、はい、通常盤もございますので、ぜひお手元に取っていただけますと嬉しいです。
There's also an affordable regular edition. This one doesn't have a signature, but I'd be so happy if you got a copy.
今回のライブ、そして、えー、このあとに予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、ハッシュタグ「鷹嶺ルイの反逆」となっております。
The hashtag for both this live and the upcoming mini-album is the same: "#鷹嶺ルイの反逆" (#TakaneLuiRebellion).
はい、皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくださいね。ビジュ良いっしょ？ ビジュ良いよね。
Please post a lot using the hashtag to hype it up! The visual is great, isn't it? I think it looks great!
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした。
And that concludes the announcement for the solo live and mini-album.
まだお知らせはございます。はい、お知らせと重大告知がございます。次はお待ちかねのグッズ紹介です！
But wait, there's more! I still have some updates and major announcements. Next is the merchandise showcase you've been waiting for!
はい、こちら、鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026ということで...
Here is the Takane Lui Birthday Celebration 2026 merch...
キービジュアルはですね 今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです
For the key visual, here is Takane Lui wearing the new outfit we revealed today, eating cake.
久乃のらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました 可愛いでしょ？
The illustration was drawn by Hisano Norari-sensei. Cute, isn't it?
それでは1つずつ見ていきましょう
Now, let's take a look at them one by one.
はい 1つ目はこちら アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております
First up is this Acrylic Diorama Stand.
キービジュアルを使用したアクリルジオラマになっております
It is an acrylic diorama featuring the key visual.
ルイ友さんとですね がんもも可愛いく執事風におめかしをしております 可愛い
The Luitomo and Ganmo are also dressed up nicely as butlers. So cute!
はい 続いてはこちら
Next up is this one.
新衣装にね こちら 新衣装のこちらとかについている 2種類のエムブレムをモチーフにしたピンバッジでございます
These pin badges are modeled after the two types of emblems found on my new outfit.
色んなところに付けて 密かにルイ友アピールをしてください お洒落でしょ？ はい
Put them in various places to subtly show off that you're a Luitomo! Stylish, right?
続いてはこちら
Next up is this one.
新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます お洒落
This is a pouch modeled after the new outfit. So stylish!
裏面はですね メッシュポケットになっているので 缶バッジはもちろん 今回一緒に販売するピンバッジも付けやすいデザインになっております
The back features a mesh pocket, making it easy to attach can badges and the pin badges sold with it.
最後はこれ欲しかったんじゃないかな？ こちら
Lastly, I bet many of you wanted this! Here it is.
はい 新衣装のショートパンツバージョンの ホロフレと同じくらいのサイズのぬいぐるみです 可愛い
It's a plushie of the short-pants version of my new outfit, about the size of a Holo-Friends plush! So cute!
ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです よろしくお願いします
I'd be so happy if you welcomed it home. Thank you!
フルセット購入特典はこちら
And here is the Full Set Purchase Bonus.
ポストカードになっておりまして 数量限定版と通常版がございます
It's a postcard, available in both limited and regular editions.
数量限定版は直筆サインが付きます たくさん用意しておるので ゆっくり選んでください
The limited edition comes with a hand-signed autograph. I've prepared plenty, so please take your time.
販売開始はですね 少し余裕を持たせて21時15分からカートオープンです 以上 グッズ紹介でした
Sales will start at 21:15 to give you some time. That's all for the merch introduction!
そしてもう1つ 重大告知です こちら
And there's one more major announcement! Here it is.
なんと 私が夢見ていました BAYFM78さんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しました
Unbelievably, my dream has come true: I've landed a regular radio program on BAYFM78!
放送日時は毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分 初回放送日は7月3日金曜日となっております規定しました
It will air every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57, with the first broadcast on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用のお便りを募集するので メールアドレスも公開しますので Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします 楽しみにしててね
We'll be accepting letters for the first broadcast on X and sharing the email. Please follow my X account! Look forward to it!
はい 次の曲が最後の曲になります 先ほども紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして 名前は「Soar」と言います
All right, the next song will be the last. It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled "Soar."
はい ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきました
I wanted to sing this with everyone at my solo concert, so I made this song where we can shout together.
ナナホシ管弦楽団さんに書き下ろしていただいた爽やかな楽曲になっております
It's a refreshing song written by Nanahoshi Orchestra-san.
このあと21時から 21時ちょっと過ぎかも知れないけど ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります
After this, starting at 21:00—though it might be slightly past—the music video will premiere!
楽曲は本日24時にリリースです この曲はですね コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております ライブまでにたくさん聴いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです
The song releases tonight at 24:00. The chorus is sung by other Hololive members! I hope you listen to it a lot!
では早速 聴いていただきましょう はい 皆さんと一緒に歌いたい曲 「Soar」です どうぞ
Without further ado, let's listen to it. The song I want to sing with all of you: "Soar." Here you go!
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
Calling your name over and over, I'll keep walking on.
一歩 踏み出したらもう未来さ
Once you take a step, it's already the future.
昨日 つまずいた道も 今日からは近道だ
Even the road I stumbled on yesterday is a shortcut from today.
息をするたびに広がる景色
With every breath, the scenery expands.
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me it's okay to believe in myself.
つぶやきも希望になって
Even whispers turn into hope,
あふれては声になって
overflowing and turning into voices.
何度 目を閉じても消せないな
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう 抑えきれない
I can fly high, right? I can't hold it back.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives me permission to spread my wings...
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is surely proof that we are moving forward...
君に伝えるんだ
I'll convey this to you.
どんな重力も心までは 縛れない 曲げられない
No matter the gravity, it can't bind or bend my heart.
この手で確かめたい
I want to confirm it with these hands.
胸焦がした思いで 爪痕をさぁ刻んで
With feelings that scorched my chest, let's carve our mark...
嵐の空模様 切り裂いて
tearing through the stormy sky.
もっと輝くよ そうだろう
I'll shine even brighter, right?
叫べばいい
Just shout it out.
憧れより眩しい歌 そして激しい唄
A song more dazzling than aspiration, and a fierce melody.
いつか耳を塞いだ
Those hands that once covered...
その両手が きっと翼になる
...your ears will surely become wings,
そう思うんだ
I truly believe so.
ゆずれない衝動
This unyielding impulse.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
I can fly high, right?
抑えられない
It cannot be contained.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives me permission to take flight,
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate anymore.
向かい風も きっと進んでる
Even a headwind is surely proof...
証拠だって
...that I am moving forward,
君に伝えるんだ
I will convey this to you.
何度でも 君を呼んで
No matter how many times, I will call your name...
また歩いてゆく
...and keep walking forward.
皆さん本日は生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday celebration today!
ソロライブ楽しみにしててね！
Please look forward to my solo live concert!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!